Xavier University Planning and Development Committee records
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections
Xavier University Planning and Development Committee records
1968-1973
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections Phone: 513-745-4821 http://www.xavier.edu/cm/archives
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Planning and Development Committee
1.25 linear feet (3 boxes)
Meeting minutes and committee documents of the Xavier University Planning and Development Committee. Included in the collection is the Five Year Planning Report issued by the consulting firm G.A. Brakeley Company, which firm worked with this Xavier committee.
XUA-18
History of Xavier University Planning and Development Committee
In early October, 1968 President Paul O'Connor, S.J. established the Planning and Development Committee. Its task was to work with the consulting firm G.A. Brakeley Company to plan the course of Xavier University for the next five years. The work of the committee was used to help prepare the 1969 consulting firm's comprehensive plan for the university, The Five Year Planning Report. The committee was apparently discontinued in 1973.
Sometime in early October, 1969, President Paul O'Connor, S.J. established the Planning and Development Committee. Its task was to work with the consulting firm G.A. Brakeley Company to plan the course of Xavier University for the next five years. The ultimate goal was to organize Xavier's first capital gifts campaign, known as the Xavier University Advancement Fund Campaign, which was launched in mid-June, 1972. From October, 1968 to March, 1969 the committee held twelve meetings with representatives of the consulting firm to prepare a comprehensive work called The Five Year Planning Report (1969-1974) which the Brakeley Company submitted to Fr. O'Connor in April, 1969. With the approval of the Board of Trustees, the committee held a series of meetings from early January to May, 1970, to clarify and refine the objectives of the planning report and the forthcoming capital gift's campaign. The committee was declared a standing committee in 1970 and continued in existence until the end of the 1972-73 academic year when it was apparently discontinued. The charge of the committee as found in the 1971-72 Description of Committees was stated as the following: "The University Committee on Planning and Development meets on call from its chairman, the Vice President for Administration, to discuss plans for new constructions, substantial renovations and general development of the campus. Including faculty,students and administrators, the Committee reports directly to the Provost."
Scope and Content
Meeting minutes, related documents, correspondence of the Xavier University Planning and Development Committee (1968-1973). Included is the three volume report of the G.A. Brakeley Company: Volume 1: Long Range Planning Study (1969-1974), Planning and Development Committee Planning Report,Autumn/Winter 1968/1969; Volume 2: Case Statement for Xavier University; Volume 3: April 1969 Report to Xavier University on the Feasibility of a New Fund-Raising Campaign for All Capital Purposes and Increasing the Return from Existing Current Support Fund-Raising Operations in the Five Year Period 1970-1975 and for Additional Capital Fund-Raising Campaigns in Later Years.
Statement of Arrangement
Materials are arranged in chronological order in this manner:
Meeting minutes, papers and other documents, 1968-1969
The Brakeley Report, 1969
Meeting minutes, papers, memos and annual report, 1970-1973
Restrictions on Access
Restricted access. Please contact the Xavier University archives staff.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects:
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio)--Planning; Brakeley (G.A.) & Co.; Educational fund raising--Ohio
Detailed Description of The Collection
- Planning and Development Committee Meeting, 1968 October 31 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Planning and Development Committee Meeting, 1968 November 6 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Planning and Development Committee Meetings, 1968 November (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Planning and Development Committee Meetings, 1968 November-December (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Planning and Development Committee Meetings, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Planning and Development Committee Meetings, 1969 January-March (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Planning and Development Committee Planning Manual, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Planning Manual (Version 2), 1969 (Box 2, Folder 7A)
- Interviews, 1969 January (Box 2, Folder 7B)
- Correspondence, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 7C)
- Planning and Development Committee Brakeley Report, Volume 1, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Planning and Development Committee Brakeley Report, Volume 1 (copy 2), 1969 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Planning and Development Committee Brakeley Report, Volume 2, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Planning and Development Committee Brakeley Report, Volume 3, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Planning and Development Committee Brakeley Report, Volume 3 (copy 2), 1969 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Planning and Development Committee Meetings, 1970 January (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Planning and Development Committee Meetings, 1970 February (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Planning and Development Committee Meetings, 1970 March-April (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Planning and Development Committee Meetings, 1970 April-May (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Planning and Development Committee Objectives, 1970 May 28 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Planning and Development Committee Memos and Reports, 1970; 1973; Undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Report on Governance, 1970 June (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 20)